Guide to the Erica Jong papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Writings, 1937-2011
  - Subseries II. 2: Fiction, 1973-2011
    This series consists of notes, outlines, drafts, correspondence, and publicity materials pertaining to Jong’s major published novels, including Fear of Flying, Any Woman’s Blues, Fanny: Being the True History of the Adventures of Fanny Hackabout-Jones, How to Save Your Own Life, Parachutes & Kisses, Sappho’s Leap, and others. The bulk of this subseries is made up of multiple drafts of each novel and includes some handwritten sections, typescript manuscripts, and publishers' proofs and galleys. Also here are drafts of Jong’s children’s book, Molly’s Book of Divorce, and the typescript of an unpublished novel entitled 2040, Sugar in My Bowl, a treatment for The Scam: A Caper Novel, and Stratford Will.
    - 2040, 1990-1992
      - Drafts, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Notes, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "Adventures of a Fat Girl in New York City," Undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Any Woman's Blues, 1988-1990
      - Ballata di Ogni Donna, 1989-1990
        - Italy,1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 24 to 25)
        - Uncut Cover, 1989 (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - Catalogue Copy, 1988-1989 (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, 1986-1991
        - General, 1986-1988, Undated (14 of 54 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 2 to 15)
        - General, 1986-1988, Undated (14 of 54 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1 to 14)
        - General, 1986-1988, Undated (13 of 54 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 1 to 13)
        - General, 1986-1988, Undated (13 of 54 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 13)
        - "Alternate Endings," 1988-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 14 to 15)
        - "Changes Entered and Reprinted," 1989 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - "Chapter III: Strong Woman Blues," Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Copy-Edited, 1991, (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 2 to 4)
        - "Dutch Edition," 1991, (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 5 to 7)
        - Early Drafts, Undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - "Erica's Working Draft," 1988, (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 9 to 11)
        - "E's New Working Draft," 1989 (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 12 to 13)
        - "Final Foreword Afterword," 1989 (Box 17, Folder 14)
        - "Final MS Copy," 1989 (1 of 3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 15)
        - "Final MS Copy," 1989 (2 of 3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 1 to 2)
        - "Glady's Suggestions," 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - "A Life in Progress," 1988, (8 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 4 to 11)
        - "The Notebooks of Isadora Wing," 1988, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 12 to 13)
        - "Rennie's Edits," 1988 (4 of 5 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 14 to 17)
        - "Rennie's Edits," 1988 (1 of 5 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - "Revisions," 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - "Rough," Undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - "Some Object of Love," Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 4 to 7)
        - "Uncorrected + Journal," Undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - "With Apparatus Now Out," 1989, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 9 to 11)
      - Floppy Disks, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - German Reviews and Publicity, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Harper & Row Packet, 1990, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 14 to 15)
      - "Misc. AWB," Undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Panel Discussion, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - "Permissions (Music)," 1989 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Posters, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Press Tour, 1990, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 20 to 22)
      - Proofs, 1989, (6 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 6)
      - "U.K. Reviews," 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Fanny: Being the True History of the Adventures of Fanny Hackabout-Jones, 1976-1980
      - Book Tour, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Drafts, 1976-1980
        - General, Undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - Afterward, Undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - Copyeditor Draft, 1980 (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 12 to 15)
        - Covers--Paperback Edition, Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
        - Cut Galleys, 1980, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 17 to 19)
        - "Earlier Version," Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - "Early Draft of Proposal," 1976 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Edited Xerox, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 3 to 6)
        - "Erica’s Corrections", 1979 (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Final Copyedited Draft, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 9 to 12)
        - Final Draft #3, 1979 (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 13 to 17)
        - "Final Final Draft"/"Submitted Copy," Undated (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1 to 4)
        - Final Working Draft, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 5 to 8)
        - "First Serial Rights"--Playboy Serialization Letters, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 9)
        - "First Serial Rights"--Playboy Serialization Uncorrected Proofs, 1980 (Box 101, Folder 1)
        - For Copyeditor, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 10 to 13)
        - Galleys, 1980 (Box 101, Folder 2)
        - Jon’s Edits, 1979 (3 of 4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 14 to 16)
        - Jon’s Edits, 1979 (1 of 4 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - "Natalie’s Corrected Draft," Undated (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 2 to 4)
        - "Old," 1979 (4 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 5 to 8)
        - "Original," Undated (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 9 to 11)
        - "Pages," Undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
        - Photocopy, Undated, (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 13 to 15)
        - Revised Edition, 2002 (1 of 6 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 16)
        - Revised Edition, 2002 (5 of 6 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 5)
        - Rough Drafts, Undated (9 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 6 to 14)
        - Second Draft Epilogue, Undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Uncorrected Proofs, 1980 (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 2 to 4)
        - "Working Copy," Undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - Working Draft, Undated (5 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 6 to 10)
      - Dramatis Personae, Undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Film, 1981-1982
        - First Draft, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Second Draft, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Third Draft, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - German Reviews, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Jacket, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Musical, 1980-1994
        - "Alternative Opening Scene", 1991 (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - Contracts, 1980-1989 (Box 25, Folder 18)
        - Cut Pages, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 19)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Outline, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 21)
        - Draft, 1991-1996
          - General, 1991 (2 of 6 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 22 to 23)
          - General, 1991 (4 of 6 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1 to 4)
          - "Most Recent Draft", 1991 (Box 26, Folder 5)
          - Reading Copy with Music, 1996, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Notices, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Notes, 1979-1980, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 9 to 12)
      - Photos--West Wycombe, Undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Plot Outlines, 1977-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 14 to 15)
      - Publication Material, 1977-1987
        - Acropole, 1979-1981 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Arbeidespers, 1979-1981 (Box 26, Folder 17)
        - Bantam, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 18)
        - Bibliography, 1978-1981 (Box 26, Folder 19)
        - "Blurbs Extra", 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 20)
        - "Book Club", 1980 (Box 26, Folder 21)
        - Book Tour, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 22)
        - Bompiani, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 23)
        - Complimentary Copy List, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 24)
        - "Eileen Prescott," 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 25)
        - End Papers, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 26)
        - Film Correspondence, 1981-1987 (Box 26, Folder 27)
        - "Film Deal," 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 28)
        - Financial, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 29)
        - Finnish, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 30)
        - "First Serial", 1980 (Box 26, Folder 31)
        - Foreign Contracts, 1979-1983 (Box 26, Folder 32)
        - Gornall, Anthony, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Granada, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Grijalbo, 1979-1983 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Grohndahl, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Gyldenal, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Interviews, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Jacket Copy, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - New American Library Contracts and Notes, 1977-1984 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Norstedt, 1979-1981 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - "Playboy-Vernon Smith Pictures," 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Production, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Promotion and Publicity, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Publication Pictures, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - "Reviews--Luce Clipping Service", 1980 (Box 27, Folder 14)
        - Shincho Sha, 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 15)
        - Style Sheet, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 16)
        - "To the Reader", Undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
        - "Vogue", 1980 (Box 27, Folder 18)
        - Weilin and Goos (Finnish), 1982 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Publicity, 1981 (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 20 to 21)
      - Publicity Prototype, Undated (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Research Material, 1977-1978, Undated, (6 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 22 to 27)
      - Reviews, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Fear of Flying, 1973-1995
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Clippings, 1976-1982
        - French, 1976-1982 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - German, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Deborah Richards Ltd Print Quantities, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Drafts, 1973-1983
        - "Assorted Chapters & Pages--Worksheets," Undated (3 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 5 to 7)
        - "Assorted Chapters & Pages--Worksheets," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 2)
        - "Drafts and Revisions," 1973 (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 3 to 4)
        - Early Drafts," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 5 to 6)
        - "First Draft," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1 to 2)
        - "Outtakes" and Other Writings, 1970s-1983 (6 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 3 to 8)
        - "Outtakes" and Other Writings, 1970s-1983 (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1 to 2)
        - "Working," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Fan Drawing, Undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - "Foreign Remittance Info", 1977 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Promotional Material, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - "Radio Syndication", 1977 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Stage Production, 1978-1995
        - Tom Teicholz, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - Yugoslavia, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Happily Married Women, 1999-2000
      - Drafts, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Drafts, 1999-2000 (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 29 to 30)
      - Notes, Undated (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - How to Save Your Own Life, 1976-1980
      - Censorship Material, 1978-1980 (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - "Copy-Edited MS," Undated (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1 to 3)
      - "Discarded Chapters," Undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - "Isadora Goes to Hollywood," 1976 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Jacket Copy, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - "Long Galleys", 1976 (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 7 to 9)
      - Publicity Materials, Undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Publicity Packet, 1977-1979 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - "Third Isadora Book," Undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Inventing Memory, 1995-2005
      - Audio Text, 1997 (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Drafts, 1996-1997 (5 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 15 to 19)
      - Drafts, 1996-1997 (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Erica's Revised Manuscript, 1996 (4 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Notes for Revisions and Additions, 1996 (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Of Blessed Memory--With Floppy Disk, 1995-1996 (9 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 9 to 17)
      - Of Blessed Memory--With Floppy Disk, 1995-1996 (4 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Office Copy, 1997, (3 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Proofs, 1997 (4 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 8 to 11)
      - Sophia, 2005 (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Notes and Rough Drafts, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - The Man Who Murdered Poets or Growing Up Bookish, Undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Molly’s/Megan’s Book of Divorce, 1983-1987
      - Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 34, Folder 16)
      - Drafts, 1984
        - General, Undated (Box 34, Folder 17)
        - "Megan’s Book of New York," Undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - Molly’s Book of New York-- Manuscript, Undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - Proofs, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - TV Adaptation, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - TV Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - The MS Murders, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "My Life as a Dog", 1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks (Photocopies), 1980-1982 (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Parachutes and Kisses, 1982-1985
      - Book Tour Material, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Chapter Titles, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Drafts, 1983-1984
        - General, Undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
        - Chapters 1-19, 1983 (With Floppy Disks), (4 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 15 to 18)
        - Copy Edited Manuscript, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 19 to 20)
        - Copy Edited Manuscript, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Copy Editor Copy, 1984, (3 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 3 to 5)
        - "(Drafts)," Undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
        - Dreamwork Copy, Undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
        - "E's Working Draft," 1982-1983 (6 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 8 to 13)
        - "E's Working Draft," 1982-1983 (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1 to 3)
        - First Draft, Undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - First Serial, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 5 to 8)
        - First Typed Rough Draft, 1983
          - Copy, 1983, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 9 to 11)
          - October 27, 1983, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 12 to 14)
        - Latest Draft, 1981-1984
          - December 23, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 15)
          - December 23, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 1)
          - February 26, 1984, (3 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 3 to 5)
        - "MS Storage," Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 6 to 7)
        - New Draft, February 1984, (3 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 8 to 10)
        - Next-to-Last Draft, 1984 (3 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 11 to 13)
        - "P & K" Copy, Undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
        - Printout, 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 15 to 16)
        - Printout, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, 1984
          - Author's Set, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 2)
          - First, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Publisher Copy, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 4 to 7)
      - Fan Mail, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Galleys, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 9 to 10)
      - "Notes and Ideas", Undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Permissions, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Promotional Material, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Publicity, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - Reviews, 1984-1985
        - French, 1984-1985 (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 15 to 16)
        - German, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Sappho’s Leap, 2000-2004
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - Drafts, 2000-2002
        - General, 2000-2001 (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 19 to 20)
        - General, 2000-2001 (11 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1 to 11)
        - Afterword, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 12)
        - Chronological
          - Drafts, 2000 Apr- 2001 Feb (7 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 13 to 19)
          - Drafts, 2001 Feb-2002 Mar (18 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 1 to 18)
          - Drafts 2002 Mar-Oct (8 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1 to 8)
        - Chapter 19-22, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - Chapter 24, Undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
        - Chapter 28, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 11)
        - Intro Drafts, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 12)
        - Intro/Outline Drafts, Undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
        - Prologue, 2000 (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 14 to 15)
        - Prologue, Notes, and Outtakes, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - "Edits", 2002 (3 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 17 to 19)
      - "Erica’s Revisions", 2002 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - "Erica’s Revisions", 2002 (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1 to 2)
      - "Revisions", 2002 (3 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 3 to 5)
      - Research, 2000-2002
        - General, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - "Ancient Greece", 2001 (Box 43, Folder 7)
        - Articles, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Notes, 2000-2001 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - The Scam: A Caper Novel, Undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Serenissima, 1984-1989
      - Correspondence and Research Materials, Undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Drafts, 1984-1987
        - General, Undated (7 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 12 to 18)
        - General, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
        - 1, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 2 to 3)
        - 2--with hand corrections, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 4 to 5)
        - 3, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 6 to 9)
        - "1st Draft", Undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
        - "Alternate Revision", 1986 (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 11 to 12)
        - "Copy Second Draft," Undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
        - "E’s Final Revision," 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 14 to 15)
        - "E’s Revisions," 1985 (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 16 to 17)
        - "E’s Working Draft", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 18)
        - Editor’s Corrections, 1986 (3 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1 to 3)
        - "Erica’s Working Draft-Draft #2," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Final, Undated (3 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 6 to 8)
        - "Final Draft," 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Galleys, 1987
          - "Author’s Marked Set," 1987 (Box 45, Folder 11)
          - "Master," 1987 (Box 45, Folder 12)
        - "Hand Written Drafts," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 13 to 14)
        - "Nan's Last Edit," 1987, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 15 to 16)
        - Notes, 1984-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 1 to 2)
        - "Odd Pages," Undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Old Draft/First Edits, Undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - "Penultimate," Undated (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 5 to 6)
        - "Ronnie’s Notes", 1986 (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - "Rough Drafts," Undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
        - Uncorrected Proof, 1987 (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Working Copy, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Publicity Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Research, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - Reviews--Drafts and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Screenplay, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Some Object of Love--Drafts, Undated (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Stratford Will, Undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - The Thirty-Ninth Year of Meredith Binder, Undated (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II.3: Non-Fiction, 1937-1999
    Arranged alphabetically, included here are Erica Jong’s published and unpublished non-fiction works, both longer, book-length works (including The Devil at Large, Fear of Fifty, Witches) as well as shorter pieces and essays. The working drafts are often heavily annotated. Related materials, including correspondence, notes, interviews, clippings, offprints, printouts, and photographs, have been kept in their original arrangement.
    Some Henry Miller correspondence, which pre-dates Jong's acquaintance with Miller, as well as the Jong-Miller correspondence is located in this subseries.
    - The Devil at Large, 1937-1992
      - 60 Minutes--Transcript, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - Claus Lutterbeck Article, undated (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1990s
        - General, 1974-1992, undated (Box 46, Folder 21 to 22)
        - Typed with Notes, 1990s (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - Cover Proofs, undated (Box 100, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, 1988-1992
        - General, 1992 (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 24 to 25)
        - "Born Hungry," 1992 (Box 46, Folder 26)
        - Chapters III & IV, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 27)
        - "Copies of Speigel Piece," 1991 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Early Drafts with Notes, 1988-1990, Undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
        - "EJ on HM [Henry Miller]," 1992, (12 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 3 to 14)
        - "HM," 1989 (Box 47, Folder 15)
        - "Henry and Me," 1992 (Box 47, Folder 16)
        - "Henry Miller: The Last Man Alive," Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 17 to 18)
        - "Just a Brooklyn Boy," 1992 (Box 47, Folder 19)
        - "Just a Brooklyn Boy," 1992, (7 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 1 to 7)
        - "Must We Burn Miller?" 1991-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 8 to 9)
        - "Sex-Libris," 1991 (Box 48, Folder 10)
        - "Sexomania/Sexophobia," 1992, (3 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 11 to 13)
        - "Tropic of Henry," 1991 (Box 48, Folder 14)
        - Typewritten, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 15)
        - Working, 1990-1991, Undated (4 of 8 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 16 to 19)
        - Working, 1990-1991, Undated (4 of 8 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1 to 4)
      - "Fear and How it Gets That Way," 1976 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - George Belmont French Bio, Undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - "Henry Miller," 1984, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Henry Miller Materials, 1937-1989
        - General, 1937-1976, (11 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 8 to 18)
        - Crazy Cock, 1989, Undated (4 of 7 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 19 to 22)
        - Crazy Cock, 1989, undated (Box 50, Folder 1 to 3)
        - "Material," 1989, Undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Molloch, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 5 to 6)
        - Published Pieces--With Notes, 1937-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 7 to 9)
      - "Henry Miller Versus the Politically Correct," 1982-1992 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - "HM Book Related Material," 1992 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - "HM Tribute," 1989 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Interview Transcripts, 1969-1990
        - Jong and Belmont, 1990, (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 13 to 14)
        - Miller and Bradley, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - "Jong/Miller Correspondence"--Originals, 1974-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 16 to 18)
      - Lawrence Durrell Interview, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - Miller Interview Carbons, 1991 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - "Milleriana,"--Henry Miller Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - Photographs, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - Publication--General, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Essays, 1967-1999
      - General, 1960s-1999, (14 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 14)
      - Andrea Dworkin Interview and Information, 1984-1987 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - "Beauty and the Beast: A Girl's Guide to Men," 1988 (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - "Blood and Guts," 1980 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - "Book of Essays and Assorted Prose," 1970s, Undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Collected Essays, 1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 19 to 20)
      - "Class News Parody", 1972 (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - "Crow at the Y: An Evening With Ted Hughes," 1971 (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - "Current Unfinished Business," 1973-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 1 to 2)
      - "Erotic Writing By Women", Undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - "East-West Blues: A New Yorker Goes West," 1976-1987 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - 'The Federation of Creators," 1995 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - "Fetal Heartbeat," 1978-1979 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - "The Forbidden City: Venice", 1985 (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 7 to 8)
      - "Giving Birth to Life," 1970s (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - "Goodbye to Henry-san" Proofs, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - "Good Girl," Undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Hillary Clinton, 1999 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - "How I Write," 1974-1987, Undated (Box 52, Folder 13)